Guide to the Cedric N. Chatterley Photographs, 1983-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Cedric N. Chatterley 1983-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Chatterley, Cedric N., 1956-
11.6 Linear Feet 719 Items
Documentary photographer based in South Dakota.
The photographs of Cedric N. Chatterley span the years 1983-2008, and follow his career as a documentary photographer. The photographs are primarily gelatin silver black-and-white prints ranging in size from 8x10 to 18x24 inches. Although Chatterley's areas of interest are broad, the most prominent themes in his work are labor, community, and religious expression. Chatterley has photographed chicken slaughterhouse workers in Maine, Cambodian immigrants in North Carolina, blues musicians in Mississippi, and tornado survivors in South Dakota. The collection is comprised of nine series titled thematically: a Career Retrospective, with nine sub-series including Social Events, Religious Iconography, Labor, Southern Landscapes, Travel, Family, Maine Folklife, TROSA, and Downeast North Carolina; Holy Land, USA; MFA Thesis; Penobscot Poultry; David "Honeyboy" Edwards; Spencer, South Dakota; Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers (TROSA);Other Images; and Other Materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, all reproduction requires permission of the photographer who retains the copyrights.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Some use copies are available.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Cedric N. Chatterley Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008 and 2009.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1956 May 6 Born in Massena, New York
1987 May Master of Fine Arts thesis, Ambivalent Ecstasies/Converging Energies, exhibited at the University of Southern Illinois, Carbondale
1988-1989 In collaboration with Steven Cole, conducted six interviews with Linda Lord about her work at Penobscot Poultry in Maine
1999 Publication of I Was Content and Not Content: the Story of Linda Lord and the Closing of Penobscot Poultry, authors Alicia Rouverol and Steven Cole, photographs by Chatterley (Southern Illinois Press)
2002 July Production completed of Honeboy, a film documentary on bluesman David "Honeyboy" Edwards, with photographs contributed by Chatterley, directed by Scott L. Taradash
2003 "Each One, Teach One" exhibit on the Durham, N.C. Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers (TROSA) program, featuring materials from ethnographic research conducted by Barbara Lau and Chatterley through the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University
2003-2005 From Cambodia to Greensboro: Tracing the Journeys of New North Carolinians, curated by Barbara Lau, photographs by Chatterley; organized by the Greensboro Historical Museum, Greensboro, North Carolina
2006 Began making his own large format cameras
Collection Overview
The photographs of Cedric N. Chatterley span the years 1983-2008, and follow his career as a documentary photographer. The photographs are primarily gelatin silver black and white prints ranging in size from 8x10 to 18x24 inches. Although Chatterley's areas of interest are broad, the most prominent themes in his work are community, labor, and religious expression. The collection is comprised of eight photographic works series titled thematically: Career Retrospective, with nine sub-series including Social Events, Religious Iconography, Labor, Southern Landscapes, Travel, Family, Maine Folklife, TROSA, and Downeast North Carolina; Holy Land, USA, an abandoned religious theme park in Connecticut; MFA Thesis, consisting of the body of work for Chatterley's Fine Arts thesis, Ambivalent Ecstasies/Converging Energies; Penobscot Poultry, a project during which Chatterley also interviewed Maine poultry worker Linda Lord; David "Honeyboy" Edwards, images of an African-American blues musician from Mississippi; Spencer, South Dakota, on a small town devastated by a tornado and then rebuilt; Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers (TROSA), a project documenting communities in Durham, North Carolina undertaken with Barbara Lau of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University; and Other Images, several miscellaneous black and white prints, some of which were shot with Chatterley's home-built cameras.
A final series entitled Other Materials consists of publication materials relating to From Cambodia to Greensboro, a documentary work on Cambodian immigrants in North Carolina that includes images taken by Chatterley, and five audio cassette tapes containing an interview with Chatterley about his career as a documentary photographer. The cassettes have been converted to digital files and use copies are available for access. Original recordings are closed to use.
The bulk of the collection is comprised of the series Penobscot Poultry and David "Honeyboy" Edwards, and Spencer, South Dakota. Series are arranged in rough chronological order; prints are in original order as received.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Chatterley, Cedric N., 1956-
Chatterley, Cedric N., 1956- --Interviews
Edwards, Honeyboy
Lau, Barbara (Barbara A.)
Lord, Linda, 1948-
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
Penobscot Poultry
Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers, Inc
African American musicians -- Mississippi
Blues musicians -- Mississippi -- Pictorial works
Cambodian Americans -- North Carolina
Documentary photography -- United States
Immigrants -- North Carolina
Photographers -- South Dakota
Holy Land U.S.A.(Waterbury, Conn.) -- Pictorial works
Slaughtering and slaughter-houses -- Maine
Tornadoes -- South Dakota -- Pictorial works
Belfast (Me.) -- Pictorial works
Durham (N.C.) -- Pictorial works
Mississippi -- Pictorial works
Mississippi -- Social life and customs
North Carolina -- Pictorial works
South Dakota -- Pictorial works
Spencer (S.D.) -- Pictorial works
United States -- Religion -- 20th century
Waterbury (Conn.) -- Pictorial works
Black and white photographs
Audiocassettes
Gelatin silver prints
Related Material
MF 045, One Year Later: The Closing of Penobscot Poultry and the Transition of a Veteran Employee (interviews with Linda Lord, 1988-1989 and traveling exhibit materials and recordings of forums, 1989)
University of Maine, Maine Folklife Center
Contents of Collection
- Career Retrospective Series, 1983-2007, (4 boxes)
  Consists of nine sub-series spanning Chatterley's career as a documentary photographer: Social Events, Religious Iconography, Labor, Southern Landscapes, Travel, Family, Maine Folklife, TROSA, and Downeast North Carolina, with the bulk of the series made up of Social Events and Labor. Original captions taken from back of prints. Subseries are arranged chronologically. Prints are in original order as received.
  - Social Events, 1983-2002, (2 folders)
    Thirty-nine 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting social events at various locations around the United States.
    - Female oil wrestlers and participant from the crowd. The Bermuda Triangle Bar, Reno, Nevada, 1983 Summer (Box 1)
    - Oil wrestler "Cat Woman." Reno, Nevada, 1983 Summer
    - Man at carnival. Elko, Nevada, 1983 Summer
    - Wedding party, Las Vegas, Nevada - Thanksgiving weekend, 1983
    - Wedding agent, Las Vegas, Nevada (western edge), 1983
    - Las Vegas, Nevada, New Year's Eve, 1983
    - Archie, dressed in service uniform, posing near photograph of his deceased wife. Hotel Logan, Logan, Utah, 1983
    - Mother with her children at a roller rink in Logan, Utah, 1983
    - Wet T-shirt contest at the Ban Dar, Ventura, California, 1983
    - Whip cream wrestling contestant conversing prior to match. Ventura County Fairgrounds, 1984
    - Square dance caller. Ventura County, California, 1984
    - Square dance caller. Ventura County, California, 1984
    - Square dancers. Ventura County, California, 1984
    - Full Gospel Church, Ventura, California, 1984
    - Christmas Parade, Camarillo, California, 1984
    - Boys with guns and flying kites. Lake Michigan shore, near Evanston, Illinois, 1985 Winter
    - St. Patrick's Day Parade - Chicago, Illinois, 1985
    - Middle school spring dance - near Olmstead/Grand Chain, Illinois, 1985
    - Young boxer. Houston, Texas, 1985 Summer
    - South Philadelphia, 1985
    - Preparing for the Rose Parade. Pasadena, California, New Year's Day, 1986
    - Semipro (amateur) wrestlers. National Guard Armory, Kennett, Missouri, 1986 Spring
    - Carnival, Mounds, Illinois, 1986 Fall
    - Cairo, Illinois (looking toward Commercial Street), 1986
    - King Coal Festival (Local military recruiters were on hand). West Frankfort, Illinois, 1986
    - Young man sitting with his brother's car parts. A.K.A. Car enthusiast. West Frankfort, Illinois, 1986
    - Amateur boxing match. Murphysboro, Illinois, 1986
    - Amateur boxer. Murphysboro, Illinois, 1986
    - (God Loves You) Du Quoin State Fair. Du Quoin, Illinois, 1986
    - KKK march, Staunton, Virginia, 1986
    - Zoo, Houston, Texas, 1997
    - Wedding trade show - the entrance to the Provo High School gymnasium, Provo, Utah, 1997
    - Wedding trade show, Provo High School gymnasium, Provo, Utah, 1997
    - Passion play by local high school students. Del Rapids, South Dakota, Good Friday, 1998.
    - Carson and Barnes Circus, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1998 Summer
    - Rodeo contestant, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1998
    - College radio, Kingsville, Texas, 1999 Fall
    - David Grey taking a break while skating the Eastport, Maine waterfront - on the last night it was legal, 2001 Aug.
    - Memorial Day, 2002 (the first Memorial Day following the 9-11-01 tragedy) Fulton Ferry, looking toward Manhattan, New York City
  - Religious Iconography, 1983-2007, (1 folder)
    Ten 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting religious imagery found across the United States.
    - Under a bridge near the entrance at Camarillo State Hospital. Camarillo, CA, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Churchyard, Moorpark, California, 1984
    - Gift shop - Holy Land, U.S.A., Bedford, Virginia, 1985 Summer
    - Healing. Marion, Illinois, 1985
    - Broken grave marker. Laredo, Texas, 1997 Summer
    - Passing a cross made of PVC plastic, Rt. 82. Cameron Parish, Louisiana, 1997
    - Boy riding the Brooklyn Carousel, 1999 Oct.
    - Street preacher taking a break before starting up again. Mt. Airy, North Carolina, 2000 Oct.
    - Baptism. Ashe County, North Carolina, 2000 Fall
    - Pioneer Village at the Castle Valley Pageant. Emery County, Utah, 2007 Aug.
  - Labor, 1984-2004, (2 folders)
    Thirty-two 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting work at various locations around the United States.
    - Las Vegas, Nevada, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Man cleaning bricks. Cairo, Illinois, 1986
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant - one week before closing. Belfast, Maine, 1989 Oct.
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant worker (shortly before closing completely). Belfast, Maine, 1989 Oct.
    - Moving machinery from Tretorn Etonic Shoe, Belfast, Maine. Closed fall, 1989.
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant (shortly before closing completely). Belfast, Maine, 1989
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant. Belfast, Maine, 1989
    - Bates Fabric Mill (operating @ 10% capacity). Lewiston, Maine, 1989 Fall and 1989, (8 prints)
    - Oil field workers on a drilling rig. Western Kansas, 1997 Summer
    - Sugarcane processing plant. Jeanerette, Louisiana, 1997 Oct.
    - Sugarcane processing plant-furnaces in the basement. Jeanerette, Louisiana, 1997 Oct.
    - Stoking the furnace inside a sugarcane processing plant. Jeanerette, Louisiana, 1997 Oct.
    - White Woman Creek, western Kansas, 1997 Fall
    - Cotton weigh station, Tallulah, Louisiana, 1997. (Archivally processed, printed winter 2002)
    - Jimmy Cox holding the knife he used for 20 years to cut open boxes of cans. Stinson's Sardine Cannery (a few weeks after closing). Lubec, Maine, 1999
    - Parking lot attendant. Salt Lake City, Utah, 2000
    - Raising the largest circus tent in the world. Carson and Barnes 5 Ring Circus, Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 Summer
    - Men raising the largest circus tent in the world-Carson and Barnes Circus. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 Summer
    - Carson and Barnes Circus worker setting up for evening's performance. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 Summer
    - Carson and Barnes Circus - father and son team practicing before performance. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001
    - Road construction worker. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 2002 Oct.
    - Sue (far left), construction worker. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 2002 Oct.
    - Hot tar roofer, on top of Aberdeen Municipal Building. Aberdeen, South Dakota, 2002 Nov.
    - Marcus, working on the "Phillips to the Falls" project. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2004 Summer
    - Participant in Pachy Burn's "Jam to Lamb" event. Greenough, Montana, 2004
  - Southern Landscapes, 1985-1995, (1 folder)
    Six 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints of scenes from across the American South and Midwest.
    - $16 hotel room, Vicksburg, Mississippi, 1985 Summer (Box 3)
    - Sign shop, Louisville, Kentucky, 1986
    - George. Cairo, Illinois, 1986
    - Women tying tobacco, southern Virginia, 1994
    - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1995
    - Burnt car, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1995
  - Travel, 1985-2001, (1 folder)
    One folder containing 22 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting Chatterley's travels in Mexico, England, Ireland, and Italy.
    - Tijuana, Mexico, Christmas Eve, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Mexicali, Mexico, New Year's Eve, 1985
    - School children visiting the Open Air Museum near Iron Bridge. England, 1996 Sept.
    - Young man on double-decker bus, west of Liverpool, England, 1996 Sept.
    - Commuters on a train from Liverpool to London express, 1996 Oct.
    - Belfast, Northern Ireland. 1996 Oct.
    - John showing me the self-inflicted razor wounds on his neck. Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1996 Oct.
    - Young man jumping from one rock to another. Housing projects, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1996 Oct.
    - Londonderry, Northern Ireland, 1996 Oct.
    - Dublin, Ireland, 1996 Oct.
    - Passing William Butler Yeats' grave, western Ireland, 1996 Oct.
    - Basilica of San Francesco, Assisi, Italy, 2000 Nov.
    - Basilica of San Francesco, Assisi, Italy, 2000 Nov.
    - Genoa, Italy - looking west, 2000 Nov.
    - Verona, Italy, 2000 Nov.
    - Catholic Church official in back seat of limousine. Rome, Italy, 2000 Fall
    - Man securing his license to "perform" for tourist. Rome, Italy, 2000
    - Rome, Italy, 2000
    - Dorf Tyrol, Italy, 2000
    - Perugia, Italy, 2000
    - Man boarding a bus in a small town in Northern Italy, 2001 Nov.
    - Young visitors at Riseria di San Saba, Italy's only WWII concentration camp - now a museum/memorial, 2001
  - Family, 1988-2007, (1 folder)
    Nine 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting members of Chatterley's family, including two self-portraits.
    - Betsy. Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1988 Summer (Box 4)
    - My sister, Nancy Jane, receiving treatment for cancer (she died two weeks later). Ventura, California, 1989 Summer
    - Self portrait - Ebb Tide Motel. Brewer, Maine, 1991 Winter.
    - Boy playing on the same street corner in Salford, England that was once the site of my great, great grandfather's wheelsmith shop (Joseph Chatterley), 1996 Summer
    - Twins with dolls - negative found in a trash dumpster in Oklahoma City (sometime in the mid 1990s).
    - My father preparing for my mother's funeral, Sioux Falls, South Dakota (she would be buried in Ventura, California next to my sister, Nancy Jane), 1998 Feb. 22 Sunday.
    - My nephew, Sgt. Timothy Hamilton, standing among a grove of trees planted in memory of the servicemen who died in a plane accident near Greenland in 1986. Fort Campbell, Kentucky, 2004 Apr.
    - Self portrait. Swimming in the ocean a few hours after my father's funeral. Ventura, California, 2004 Sept. 11
    - Street musician playing "Come, come ye saints" on his harmonica. Temple Square, Salt Lake City, Utah, 2007 Aug.
  - Maine Folklife, 1990, (1 folder)
    Three 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting basket-making in Maine.
    - Richard Sillabay searching for Brown Ash to make baskets. Aroostook County, Maine, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Joseph Tomah, basket maker. Houlton, Maine, 1990
    - Joseph Tomah's kitchen table. Houlton, Maine, 1990
  - TROSA, 2002, (1 folder)
    One 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver print. See also the main series in this collection entitled Triangle Residence Options for Substance Abusers.
    - Man cleaning hallway at "T-North" (TROSA's building that was once a school). Durham, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Downeast North Carolina, 2004, (1 folder)
    Five 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints of images taken by Chatterley during the summer of 1994 in Halifax County, North Carolina.
    - Hog kill, 4th of July weekend, Halifax County, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Hog killing, July 4th weekend, Halifax County, North Carolina, 2004
    - Scotland Neck, North Carolina, 2004 July 4
    - Ahoskie, North Carolina, 2004 Summer
    - Golden Corral Restaurant, Ahoskie, North Carolina, 2004
- Holy Land USA Series, 1985-1986 and undated, (3 boxes)
  Consists of 50 8x10 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints and one larger laminated color placemat. Built in 1958, Holy Land USA was a religious roadside attraction in Waterbury, Connecticut. The images document the condition of the park, which closed in 1984 after 26 years of operation. Original captions taken from back of prints. Many of the images were printed in 2001. Prints are in original order as received.
  - Entrance at front gate. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Display at front entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Front entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Near front entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Display inside Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Adam and Eve at the Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Far end of the Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Vandalized Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Entrance to Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Vandalized/weathered display inside Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Display inside Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Vandalized crucifix inside the Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT 1985
  - Replica tomb (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985
  - Hillside at night. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Front gate/entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Canteen - to the left of the main gate. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - One of several pathways. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Near the top of the hill. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Detail of Mt. Transfiguration. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on far hillside. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display near chapel. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display near chapel. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Pathway to Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Wall along the side of the Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display near the Catacomb entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display inside Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Sums everything up doesn't it? Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display near the Catacombs (printed 1995). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Small tombstones, near front entrance (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - The Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Vandalized display of Mary and Joseph (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Jesus says "Begone Satan." (printed 2001) Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Near the highest point of Holy Land, USA (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Statue on hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display by hillside, near the chapel (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Weathered display near chapel (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Wall near chapel (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Top of the hill, overlooking Waterbury (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Glass display case (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display on hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display near Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Inside the Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display inside the Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Display inside Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986
  - Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT. Photographed 1986, printed 2001. Archivally processed. Original Oriental Seagull paper.
  - Holy Land Replica. Waterbury, Conn. - 11.25x17.5 color placemat (Box 14)
- MFA Thesis Series, 1987, (2 boxes)
  Consists of three 11x14 and 40 18x24 gelatin silver prints for Chatterley's Master of Fine Arts thesis at Southern Illinois University at Carbondale, entitled Ambivalent Ecstasies/Converging Energies. This body of work explores religious ecstatic experience. The three 11x14 prints offer a panoramic shot of the thesis exhibit, while the forty 18x24 prints form the body of work for the thesis project. The prints have no captions but are numbered sequentially, with information included that indicates their positions in the exhibit, and the date of the exhibit, May 6, 1987.
  - 11x14 Prints:
    - 11x14 print titled MFA thesis exhibit, Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, IL, 1987 May 6 (Box 7)
    - MFA thesis exhibit, Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, IL
    - MFA thesis exhibit (self-portrait), Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, IL
  - 18x24 Prints:
    - MFA thesis #1
    - MFA thesis #2
    - MFA thesis #3 (small cross dangling from hand-held Bible)
    - MFA thesis #4 top (above #5, bottom)
    - MFA thesis #5 bottom (below #4, top)
    - MFA thesis #6 top (above #7, bottom)
    - MFA thesis #7 bottom (below #6, top)
    - MFA thesis #8 top (above #9, bottom)
    - MFA thesis #9 bottom (below #8, top)
    - MFA thesis #10 top (above #11, bottom)
    - MFA thesis #11 bottom (below #10, top)
    - MFA thesis #12 top (above #13, bottom)
    - MFA thesis #13 bottom (below #12, top)
    - MFA thesis #14 top (above #15, bottom)